# **ASHISH BARAVALIYA**

<u>ashishbarvaliya.job@gmail.com</u> | <u>ashishbaravaliya.com</u> | Sarnia, ON

### **Profile**

I am an experienced software developer with over **4+ years** of work experience in a multinational corporation in India, currently **pursuing** post-graduation studies in full-stack software development. Additionally, working as a **senior software developer** for freelance projects on a part-time basis, I also contribute to open-source projects for platforms like <u>Parse Community</u> and <u>Directus</u> among others.

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/ashishbarvaliya</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/AshishBarvaliya</u>

## **Education**

**Lambton College** 

September 2022 - April 2024

Post-Graduation in Full Stack Software Development 3.5/4.0

Gujarat Technological University Bachelors in information technology 7.5/10 August 2015 - May -2019

### **Skills**

Languages: JavaScript, Typescript, Python, C#, HTML

Frameworks: React.js, Next.js, Vue.Js

Tools: Azure, AWS, Git, Docker, Firebase, GCP

**Frontend:** MUI, Tailwind CSS, Styled-component, Storybook, SCSS, Ant Design **Backend:** Node, SQL, .NET, GraphQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Prisma ORM, Drizzle ORM

Soft Skills: Problem solving, Quick learner, Team player, Creativity.

## **Work History**

**Freelance** Remote

Senior Software Developer

August 2022 - Present

- Managing a SAAS marketplace web app single-handedly in a small startup, including overseeing all aspects of its development and operation
- Completed over **five projects**, including OpenAI apis, a payment invoice page, and a database management system. Each project involved utilizing a diverse range of skills, including front-end and back-end development.
- Gained proficiency in various areas including **Next.js**, **Ant Design**, **Tailwind CSS**, **Docker**, **AWS**, Stripe, **Netlify CMS**, and **Team leading**.

**Kerv Digital** 

Bengaluru, India

Software Developer

December 2019 - August 2022

- In the role of a frontend developer for **2.5+ years**, responsibilities included implementing frontend designs, collaborating with teams to **deliver high-quality results**, and **presenting** work to clients.
- Developed a web portal for **LearnLight** with React, TypeScript and **Apollo GraphQL**. The portal allows LearnLight users to view profile information, keep track of learning resources and activities.
- Developed web portal with a big team for the Scouts of UK. The portal enables users to apply for permits and effectively manage profiles. utilized React, Styled Components, Redux Toolkit, and Azure to deliver a seamless user experience.

## **Projects**

#### Theme AI (Product) [2023]

- Launched this own product in 2024.
- Product "Select AI-Enhanced Meaningful Themes for Your Web Design"
- Tech stack Typescript, Next.js, ShadCn, Drizzle ORM, PostgreSQL, Stripe, Next Auth.
- Monthly new users ~100 and Page view ~1000.
- https://www.themeai.io/

#### Portfolio app [2023]

- Created my portfolio website using Reactjs, SCSS with Sanity CMS.
- <u>github.com/AshishBarvaliya/portfolio-web</u>

#### Booksaw web app [2022]

- Implemented a single-page web application for a bookstore boasts of full responsiveness.
- Skills showcase React, Typescript, MUI, enlist, husky and MUI Theming
- github.com/AshishBarvaliya/bookstore

#### **Vortex sales engine** [2022]

- Developed a single page web app to highlight these skills Typescript, Rebass, CSS and Styled component.
- github.com/AshishBarvaliya/vortex-sales-engine

#### **Gesture Based Home Automation** [2019]

- Created a home automation system using raspberry pi, python, and computer vision, can be used by people with disabilities (mute and deaf) to control home appliances by making a few hand gestures to the camera.
- github.com/AshishBarvaliya/Hand-gesture-detection

## **Certifications**

Python Programming Bible: Python, oops concepts, and Data structure
Project Management Simplified: Agile, Scrum, Jira, and Grant chat.

Machine learning with python by Andrew Ng: Al and ML Algorithms

Deep learning Specialization by Andrew Ng: Neural Network, Computer Vision, and NLP